In this video, I'll show how to use
在这个视频中 我将向大家展示如何使用
jupyter's nbconvert tool to change this notebook into a slide deck for presentation.
Jupyter 的 nbconvert 工具将这个 Notebook 生成幻灯片
This notebook summarizes some observations from
这个 notebook 总结了前面课程中
the car mileage dataset from earlier in the course,
对汽车燃油效率数据集的观察发现
focusing on the relationship of CO2 emissions to other features in the data set,
主要是关于二氧化碳排放量和数据中其他变量之间的关系
including engine size, and fuel mileage.
包括发动机排量大小和燃油公里数
In order to prepare the notebook for conversion,
先进行准备工作
we need to assign each cell to a specific type of slide element.
我们需要对每一个单元格的类型进行指定
To do this, click on the view menu option,
在这里点击 view 按钮
move to cell toolbar, and select slideshow.
选择cell toolbar 然后选择 slideshow
You'll see a drop-down in the upper right corner of
然后你就可以在每个单元格的右上角
each cell to assign each cell a slide type.
看到一个下拉的选项
For the markdown slides,
对于 markdown 单元格
I will assign the slide type.
我将选择 slide 这个类型
These will show up as the main flow of the slide deck.
它们是幻灯片的主体部分
For the code cells, I'll do one of two things.
对于代码单元格 我会进行一些区分
For cells like the first two,
类似前面两个代码块
we're undoing things that aren't really important to the presentation.
因为它们对于我们的演讲不重要
I'll assign them to skip so that they won't be rendered in the output.
我会选择 skip 让它们不要出现在幻灯片中
The other cells that generate the visualizations will be set as subslide types,
其他能够创造图表的代码块 我选择 subslide 类型
and will be seen after their parents slides.
它们会在父级主体幻灯片的下面展示
After doing this and saving the notebook,
完成了这些 保存 notebook
I stop the notebook server and return to the terminal.
终止 notebook 的运行 返回到terminal (终端)
To perform the conversion,
我将输入这个指令
I input the following command.
来进行格式转换
The two option specifies the HTML slides output format,
前面两个选项指定了输出的格式 即 HTML
while post serve will open up
同时 --post serve 选项会开启一个 HTTP 服务器
an HTTP server to render the slides immediately after conversion.
在会话结束后 自动渲染你的幻灯片
You can see the slide deck now rendered using reveal.gs.
现在你就可以看到你的幻灯片了
The left and right arrows onscreen,
你可以使用屏幕上的左右箭头
or with the keyboard., can be used to move between main slides.
或者键盘上的箭头 在不同的主体幻灯片之间进行切换
For slides with child subslides,
对于含有子幻灯片的主体幻灯片
you can use the up and down arrows to navigate between them.
你可以使用上下箭头进行上下页的切换
You'll notice in the visualization slides that
你可能注意到了 页面上除了图表
the code has been rendered in addition to the visualization.
还包含了代码
We'd rather this code not be visible in the presentation.
代码是演示中不需要看到的内容
To accomplish this, we can specify
这个时候 你可以指定一个模版文件
a Jinja template file to generate the slides in the format that we desire.
让幻灯片应用于我们希望的格式
This page by Damian Avila,
Damian Avila 是 nbconvert 开源项目的一个贡献者
one of the contributors to nbconvert,
在他的页面上
has an example of a template for hiding
你可以找到一个能在渲染过程中
the input cells when rendering a notebook as slides.
将代码隐藏的模版
I've made a local copy of this code as output_toggle.tpl,
我下载了这个代码 命名为 output_toggle.tpl
and put it into the same folder as my notebook.
把它放在 notebook 所在的文件夹下
Now, when I use nbconvert,
现在 当我再次使用 nbconvert
I add an additional option, template output_toggle.
加入一个额外的选项 --template output-toggle.tpl
The slope slides now only show the visualization outputs,
现在幻灯片上只能看到可视化图表了
and withhold the code inputs unless I click on the output.
除非我点击图表 才会出现代码